Ok, shall we get started us five pm
session on infrastructure as a service you guys are brave?
Exciting...big crowd I hope you guys cannot find the seats...need to find
...so my name's corey sanders...the director program management responsible for
infrastructures a service and cloud services actually in the
as your team when I before I get started me just kinda get a show hands how many people have deployed on as
your before okay how many people deployed...has on atrophy m?
Okay, a lot of people you guys sure you should be an intersection ...
will go through the right pace and make sure that we get the right stuff here and make sure to interesting
and exciting for you the goal of this session is to walk...so what we're trying to do
here today many give you kind of an overview of the platform like five not
...ten minutes to talk a little bit about how so
...all a platform is and we position infrastructures service in that platform
then we're going to do a drill into a...a service how it works some of
the components of the different aspects that we have a lot of features that have been shipped of the
last couple months and we'll be able to talk to those and bridle come up and do that and then I'll end with
...discussion on templates which we actually just announce support
...the service literally two hours ago my blog
went live so we'll be able to talk a little bit about that some of the details on how that works
...touch a little bit on visual studio integration and then we'll
be done and we'll get you on your way for the for the rest of your wednesday sound like a good
...that's basically what people expected what you going to do now I mean you could leave I guess so, ...
I can't do anything now at this point so, let me judge forward and we'll take it from there so,
the as...platform overview and this just
...give you a little touch on sort of what we're looking at
here we really think about the asher platform...really think of it with these three pictures in mind?
Very interesting pictures let me actually add some add some description
...hyper scale and this is just the ability to grow and
growing growth and I'll give you some examples of sort of what this means to us and how we think it's going to
apply as we look at the types of services and solutions that you deploy?
Enterprise grade all explain this as well this is, you know, the security and the ability to scale-up
to the solutions that you want and then hybrid which is this fun little gecko with
a ellison head-on it that's that was actually the best picture define which is sort of
a hybrid story and we'll spend a few minutes on that both how that fits in and
then we'll talk more about it when we talk about the template story later so that's actually the fun picture there so just
...microscope effective you saw this a little bit from scott this morning, you know,
the coverage the global coverage it really the growth has been it really exciting force and we
have obviously more coming all the time twenty-four team we added the blue dots two
thousand thirteen where the green dots and you know, the coming soon was the I guess there was two dots their
meta one big dot for the ones that we've announce already in india?
For me scaling...perspective excuse me scaling our perspective we really sort of want
to make sure the platform can handle all forms of scale out in
this really is some of the aspects of hyper scale that we think of it's not just the fact that
were in nineteen going on twenty-one regions but is also that those reasons have
regions have a ton of capacity and we know this because...host the capacity to run
our other services in them so the ability to scale out and handle that capacities very
...be important for you as your services grow out now scaling is not all the same thing
...give you some ideas of some of the things about scale out that we think about,
you know, this example here on the right lots of scaling up and down being able to
...massive growth in a very short period of time and then being able to scale back when
it's not needed some examples of this the asher batch service that we have an http insight which is our
who dupes service handle this type of frequent and fast scaling one of the things that I'll
talk about when I spend time on templates later one of the capabilities that we've added with
templates is fast parallel deployment so for those who have use the platform maybe
you're using our...written directly to the rest api or the accuracy
alive you may in the passive hit some locking errors right you
try to deploy one and then another vm really quickly after it and we said
hold on we're not done thinking about the first one so, that a lot of that's going to get better
and change with this type of scenario in mind so html
...actually is one of our most friendly partners deploying on the platform in that they
really push as hard to deploy lots and lots of...really quickly if you
...demo this morning if you were in...session he didn't actually hit the deployed button on the may so
...cluster but we've been able to deploy in the preview of
this new api upwards of about five hundred six hundred gm's in about, you know,
five for five minutes when they're running linux windows it takes a little longer for them to
start so this is really a big goal of ours is both having the
...handle this and then having the api to be able to handle the
calls and request that you have and this is a lot of the passion and goal around this
new api on top of this other types of scaling solutions things like
sequel database which ...actually runs on top of service fabric which was announced this morning and,
of course that runs on top of the same sort of virtual machine infrastructure that we're talking
about very different scaling pattern right this is much more focused on three maybe
...instances it ends up doing replication across them typically
it's mostly growing and rarely shrinking as the data goes up you typically don't
go back down but the key and critical point for this type
of scale is to make sure your maintaining quorum right and this is actually feedback we hear from the
sequel team and feedback we've heard from the excuse me the data...team
at the guys running cassandra making sure that they can maintain quorum...a critical part of scale
out so one of the things that we have today this concept and availability
set you can make sure that you keep this high availability bryan we'll talk about it...
the big changes with the new api that...announcing we actually have up to three fault domains now not just
too so it allows you to build these type of quorum systems in a much cleaner and higher
available way and then sort of the last one which is actually service fabric as a good example which is more of a
...structure and this ends up scaling based on the replicated
nature of that of that solution cassandra looks very similar to this where it ends up building these
...and has to scale out and this is where sort of making sure communication between your instances is going
to be fast so, for all of these we feel really excited about having the
iso platform being able to host them to enable these types of solutions that can sit right on
top and scale as needed with the capacity to grow based on customer demand?
So, enterprise grade when we think about enterprise great I'll try and I'll try and be quick on this one there's sort of
two big aspects one is security and,
the other is scale-up not to be confused with what I just walk through with scale out and the
ability to deploy whatever types of solutions are applications you may want.
So, for security...primary mechanism for security
these this is a data center that we actually have our primary mechanism for security is we
have one person that pretty much just sits there and watches now...we do
...there are more people that would've been like a roaring laughter.
Like...has whoever that was front-row here we gookay,
so, let me walk you through a little bit of the approach that we have to securityI
want-to make sure that I touch upon it we won't talk too much about it throughout but I think is really critical sort
of lay the ground the groundwork for security so the primary aspects
...we think of this and sort-of for concentric rings in as...all up right this isn't just I
...but we end up having to think about it a lot since we're sort of the lois layer the
...physical this is we lock-down data centers we lock-down
make sure that access has to have to factor off we make sure that we have cameras and,
barriers so on and this is really an important part...just assumed
part of the security story that we have when you go in from there the next one is really on our
ability to secure the software and this is sort of years and years of training
and learning in app in microsoft to be able to secure software in general so,
understanding how to do forensics
...when things are happening that don't look normal
...how to do penetration testing on our own software one of the things to think about when you look at
sort of klout and security models of
cloud the amount of data we have coming in is a gigantic compared to really
any individual provider of...infrastructure so we can see global trends on attacks
and viruses so on much quicker and we use that to be able to protect the system and
protect your applications as they deploy the next...then...security we offer you and brides going
to go into detail across a few of these areas but just to give you kind of a sense of the things we offer one
is the ability to have isolated and secure virtual networks and again with the new api to be
able to completely manage them in a template base format but then also
manage them in an imperative way using our shown the scripting...
that we offer so we'll talk a little bit later about that being able to control down access
across those virtual networks using accolade or security groups which are also part of the new api
as you can control the security groups and you can make sure that specific only specific ports
can be access between each other and you can lock-down a different areas to really make sure your
tears are under control address directory as the primary an primary
identity story so you can login and make sure that your access to the virtual machines
is restricted only to those who should get it using...access control and,
then the last...sort of go together security appliances we have a few of these already in
place we have a lot more coming down the road things like ...to be able to
lock-down your network and make sure that your securing it using a virtual appliance that deploys
...a vm and we see a lot of excitement...interest in that as we see more
and more enterprises deploying into asher with sort of a connection back home.
And, then the last of these
...concentric rings is the virtual machine and we have a few areas here
that we really like to secure one is we offer anti mahler so we offer free
...on windows that you can just click and deploy and we'll put that on your box without,
without asking you any questions we also offer a and ten-hour from partners that you can
deploy both on windows and on linux and it enables a lot of
...very easy to configuring
...and actually bryan will talk about that when he talked about extensions like I mentioned already role
base access control integrated with abstracted director a and being able to use that to
lock-down who can access what with the logging in auditing to match that to make sure you can see who
tried...a and make sure that you're that you're watching that and then the last key point
here is the key point great pun is key vault and this is a
service that's in preview right now and what this is both software and hardware
backed a keys and, secrets that you can put into our
...our...that allow you to use it for things like
encryption you can use it for things like passwords I...it offers a lot of control
their for passwords it ends up just storing it but for keys you can actually put asymmetric
keys for those who are super passion about keys and security you have...asymmetric
keys and actually run all your encryption through the system they never leave the box right so they're tied to that
ager sem they can't get off and it ends up being a very secure solution so
that's deeply integrated with gm's you can do
...the sequel server databases on there and encrypted and we'll have more and more integration with
key...over time okay?
And, the scale
options the really the way we look at this is we look at sort of the spectrum of high-value
and larger-scale up and you so you sort of...two slides one that she gave examples of using
...for scale...and it scenarios like hd insight and then
...solutions that required for scale-up scenarios a great one is, you know,
a big sequel database that you may want to deploy or even a large my sequel box that you want to
deploy you can use the scale-up sizes the
...series with four hundred forty eight
gig of memory on the box and you can use that with premium storage and,
you can get the fastest speed possible with the largest vm sizes to run those really monde
...so the overall idea is how do we make sure we can run any workload in any way
and as you look at some of the enterprise grade lift and shift type scenarios or at least partial
...or using components from the from the on prim environment into the
cloud the start becoming really exciting options for you
okay and then the last one which all...the three to talk about is the connectivity
side and we sort of really focus on connectivity in three ways like I said
we have the virtual the virtual network support where you can lock-down and gives
...actually selected the ip addresses that each one your virtual machines will get in the
cloud but they need to figure out how to connect and three options we have one is called
point to site which uses and sl base connectivityand,
what this enables is you can actually connect just from your local box using a vp
...environment and be able to treat the entire cloud is just an extension of a vp
n of your local box and I have a slide...describing that the other two are a
little bit more involved the next one is a vp and us
cost site to site and that requires a full vp and physical device to
becooked up or could be running as actually a virtual device using windows serverbut,
that requires...of vp and dedicated machine and that exposes both
sites fully so your entire enterprise site
...your entire site in as your this typically requires more involvement from the
ip pro staff right they have to get involved in sort of hooked us up and make sure the
connectivity is going to work so on it takes a little bit more time to get going ...the point to
site...express route and I'm not really it's been a lot of time on this but this is the
ability to work with these togo providers and get this sort of hardline into asher
it's typically mp less based connectivity folks like eighteen...
etc you can also hook up your stuff into a carrier hotel god-like equal x and,
you know, put in your own box in there and use that
...your connectivity mechanism as well so these obviously have a lot more throughput have dedicated lines
etc so across these three right you have
the very simple very fast very dev focused option of the
...point to site and then much more sort of full enterprise
full connectivity option dedicated line at the bottom with express route?
So, just to kinda give you a little bit more details on point...site if you had
instead of virtual machines running asher you know, front-end and back-end maybe on different subnet
right you may have just assign them all just relatively random ip addresses but they are running in
a virtual network and, you want to connect to them and do work on the right but you don't actually
...open them up to the public internetmaybe they maybe they're just facing internal sites
or internal solutions so what you can actually do with the bp and connection you
can treat them all like an extension on your box what this does is it sets a
...and connection so that it can work with a gateway that sits on our side and actually
rewrite outs the traffic on your local box to rewrite it through that
vp and into asher so it does actually restricted just to
your local box so your entire enterprise doesn't connect to it also just goes to
...four-three which means that typically no additional porting to be open
...needs to be called a you typically can make that connection and actually not have any other person
involved very much a dev friendly dev focus option free to deploy...so,
there's a few steps you have to install certain make sure the search, you know, it's a secure connection so on
but, it's a very powerful option for really fast connectivity into...
And, just kind of extended I'll talk again when I talk about the template
story later consistency story is a major portion of our overall strategy when it
comes to hybrid...and the ability to have a single place to deploy all of your
...excuse me a single platform to deploy all
your apps the template language that we're going to detail later this is the same template language that
you will see coming through for our private and hosted cloud stories which is our asher
...and this is the ability to take effectively
as your platform and launched onto a set of machines running on prim or in a hosted environment
so the benefit in our of this is actually really exciting with this new template language you
can model of fairly involved application which I'll show you an that
barely involved application will then be able to launch private cloudhostinguk cloud public
cloud and the exact same...result will come out of it
...the same solution that works and doesn't typically need to be fully tested again so
it's a really powerful...multi...option that we're hoping to enable
as part of this as your...story we actually do have a large set of
partners so the purple dots that are that are now growing onto the map
show some of the...os partners that we have in these are the folks that are running the asher
...today in production so we'll see that
continue to grow over time you can see sort of at places where maybe we don't have an
asher environment available a or places that maybe there's additional security requirements
...requirements these are hosted in private clouds that are
starting to see the benefit of that asher...again over time we'll see more and more this
grow we actually already have more than a hundred countries...six hundred local data centers
...world-class partners and...customers deployed on it every day so it's
very exciting aspect to our overall story and the template language really should
tight together ok so that's kind of...overview section I'm going to turn
...bryant's rossi now who's going to give you some of the foundational infrastructure the
service content...you how this system works what it does in the back-end when you ask
...to do things and then all of take back over for what's new so, come on,
up right great thanks very good thank you very scary...of clicker word clicker?
Fatherless known so my...as mentioned...bryant's rossi
...principle program manager on...so the as your computes engineering team
...next few minutes what I want to do is talk about some of the building blocks that make-up
infrastructures...service...as your we'll take a look at the things like the
storagecomponents the compute components as well as networking also
spend a little bit of time in some...just...highlighting what it is that we're talking about those
...mentioned all hand-up back over to korea the end who's going to give you some insight
in some of the new announcements that we've recently made some of the new technologies and where we're kind of
taking as you're in the future so we thought let's go ahead and delvin?
Let's start with storage.
So, I saw mostly...went up and said that
...created virtual machines in as you're if that is the case that,
you know, that typically when you create a virtual machine you be assigned to...
By default...virtual machine if you're running a windows operating system in the via
...obviously show up as a see drive-in...the drive the see...your system drive
this is typically where you're going to dropthe windows installation any other application
installation that you have inside the virtual machine the
see drive does have the potential for...so for you know,
both read and write cashthis is based on the as your blob underlining
stored system in addition we give you a d drive the...drive is a temporary
disk don't ever get confused by that it is not...a persistent
disk that comes with no...lays it's not using the same kind of persistent
storage that the system drive is so this is a great drive to put, you know,
temporary log files anything that doesn't need to persist anything that doesn't need to
...continue along with the via
...life additionally you can add a number of disks as data
discs so this...obviously...e driver
f drive based on the size of virtual machine you select we...the ability to
go up to sixty-four additional...attached to a single virtual machine the
...running away from me about even clicking and...moving...a move on mover so,
you can add touch up to sixty-four
additional data distort running virtual machine and just like the primary system drive it
is based on the algebra blob storage this is the standard blob storage underneath?
Now one thing that we get by default here and this is what really you know,
a data assurance statement is every time you do
...right so...the system driver one of these data
...are actually doing it in triple kit so this is ensuring that
no single drive can you...single drive loss would take down any data
so every time we do a right before it comes back and says the right as finished we've actually done it
in triple kit on three separate drives on the system that's...to ensure that no single
drive failure will take down your data this gives you the high durability that we need this is
the allay that were kind of promising with the underlining storage as well
as I mentioned we allow for up to sixty-four terabytes
...sixty-four single one terabyte drives that can be attach
...obvious use a storage pool to...the all of these together
...we're talking about right here we're going to talk about some of the advance storage options...a minute but
here we're talking about the spinning spindle drugs so we're seeing about five hundred I out
spur drive so if you were to take all sixty-four of these dries put them in a stripes set
...be seeing approximately thirty two thousand ...across the drug disk pool.
Okay, so, we talked about the fact that we're writing everything and triple
...across three different drives that protects against a single drive failure
in addition we have ways to protect against a regional disaster
one datacenter going down this is called geo replication so we have
the ability to copy your disks and your data in your virtual machines to another local
...should say regional location datacenter...kind of a balancing act here we're trying to
do two things the first thing we're trying to do is put far enough away that
a natural disaster type of event wouldn't take down both the datacenter so typically
their over four hundred miles away the second thing that we're trying to do is
...that geopolitical boundaries are still maintained so when you're deploying your virtual machines
your considering where the...are being deployed you might be under constraints
regarding geopolitical boundaries you might have compliance boundaries maybe you're in a particular industry
...vertical that requires you to...data one location so
we're doing geo replica we're not actually taking something that's in europe and
...over the united states instead we're trying to keep it
within those geopolitical boundaries and that's what you see on the map here so
the common color-coded dots indicate the regional datacenters that
we're doing geo replication across so you can see there, for example, in europe we have the to
browned dots again we're not doing a copy across these boundaries.
So, in addition to the algebra blob storage we also have algebra files
measure files is currently and preview as your files is basically another way that you
can attach storage and the...there's you can enable smb.
So, we're actually using sm btwo dot one so if you wanted if a shared
of file location or multiple virtual machines are accessing the same file share
the same time this is the way that you want to do it all actually short briefly in a demo
in a little bit again, it's currently in preview if you're interested in that feature...go to the
previous site sign up for it and they'll give you ability to the portal to go ahead and install
asher files so anything that you want to share, you know,
if you have shared settings if you have diagnostic information that you want to
share across multiple virtual machines if you
have application installation packages that you want...multiple virtual machines
is a great tool to use for those purposes.
Either as...mentions we've recently
announced premium storage with premium storage you can attach up to thirty-two
terabytes of storage per virtual machine we're seeing over sixty thousand sixty four
thousand...out per vm and a single
disc is seeing about fifty thousand audio ops we also and I'll show you in the you why
where you can enable and disable this but if you enable the cash without the cash
you're seeing about five milliseconds rewrite time and...with the cache of turned
...less than one millisecond latency for read operations against
the virtual machine it's great for dared data warehousing solutions if
you're building applications and workloads...really require fast
and scalable storage the premium storage is the way to go.
So, just visualy depiction again,
same kind of thing we now have three different locations you can go down...blobs you can go to
add your files and you can also go down to premium storage and this again applies to
your system this as well as any additional data...that you want...to the virtual machine.
The one thing I want to talk about and I'll show you where it is in the ui as well we have the concept of
virtual machine images so the key here
is basically taking a snapshot of the virtual machine and all of the attached
drives let's say I have a vienna has thirty-two attach drives I want to
go ahead and replicate that image and maybe deploy over and over again this is
a one-click button you can also obviously also do with the our
...to basically take a snapshot of that virtual machine that works regardless of
your using since proper...so a lot of people create a virtual machine
...sanitize it all censure get ready to be used as
...image they'll go ahead and do virtual machine image snapshot against that and
then they can go ahead and deploy over and over again additionally if you have all the configuration
...not...prepped you can do the same thing now
as we all know you wouldn't necessarily want to deploy it back out on the same network infrastructure
you run into a ip conflicts...run...issues licensing several pop up
so there's duplicate virtual machines but if you want...offload the virtual machine maybe you want
to know debug something maybe if you want to use in your dev devon test environment is a
really easy method of...entire vm including all of the attach discs?
All right so let's move over and talk a little bit about computes so
...mentionedsome of the new sizes of come the market...touch on just briefly here a
little more in-depth we have a serious we have a number of acer size
...out there today the...series is a newer class of...
based on newer processors so the cpu is about sixty percent faster than we see
in the existing a serious gm's we go up to one hundred
and twelve gigabytes of memory so other than the eighty-nine serious are largest
...does what I think is fifty-six gigs the largest non eighty-nine series
vm here with the tty sears we can go up to one hundred twelve gigs per vm we
also use local ss the storage now that's not for persistent stores that's actually for caching.
But, again, that's giving you much faster read access a lower latency times
and the d series is available in all regions and available today.
And, then the...we are
factual refer to this is the godzilla serious because these virtual machines are absolutely mammoth
...really optimized for data workloadsup to thirty-two cp cpu
...the largest virtual...up to four hundred
forty eight gigabytes of ram six-point-five terabytes of local
...storage it is using the latest intel processors
in these virtual machines and again, similarly you can attach up to sixty four
disks to that single...how many people are thinking they're going to use oggi series virtual machine?
They're fun they're fun all I can say is I like the fact that I don't have to pay for my
as your consumption because...since can really start out in the so.
Anyway, so,...version...but I did anyway itself...
ok so let's talk a little bit more let's keep going availability sets
so we talked about some of the data redundancy and protection we do want to disclose...you know,
with the triple...copy we talked about the fact that we do gl
of replication to make sure that you know,
if an entire datacenter goes down you have your data images
another location availability set is another way and this is really how we guarantee
rs allay so if you're looking for the three nine...nine point nine five percent of
time really going to...the deploy your virtual machines and what we refer to as and availability
set this protects against both hardware and software failure on the infrastructure itself
...supported for both windows and linux environments so essentially what we're doing
here with availability sets this is a typical rack and obviously we have multiple physical
machines...feel like the stage is going to have a natural disaster
right here on the stage...I don't know if...here but every time I take a step...cracking so,
those are the physical machines in the rack...obviously we also have the
racks which, you know, the top of racks which we also have the our units and
...obviously concerned about is what if to of your virtual machines are
on or what is what if your virtual machine or to virtual machines are working in appear or set
...load balance set or on the same physical
...what happens so what we do with availability sets as we make sure that doesn't happen you
created availability...you add your virtual machine to that
...and what algebra automatically does ensure that those virtual machines are deployed on
to physical physically different...within the same datacenter
...goes down at the our supply goes down...the networks which goes down you can make sure that
the other virtual machine that's running out workload is not in the same location so again for
high availability to get those you know,
ninety nine-point nine five percent up time desolate guarantees you
...want to create availability sets nigger one employer virtual machines into those sets?
All right so let's talk a little bit about networking.
So, load balancing...the soften times goes hand-in-hand with availability sets as well.
It asher we have the ability to essentially set up a very easy and
quick load balancing set and do load balancing in this example here
...load balancing web traffic across port eighty this works
for both internal and external environment so if you have customers coming inagain,
say wanting to hit a web server host inside of...virtual machine or if you have
internal clients that are coming through your corporate network that would work as well we support both
to...and udp traffic we also put for
...across the traffic and also recent addition is
client affinity so if you do want to clients to continually get access to the
same load balance node you can set up
...affinity...ip addresses as well so you can be assured
...same client assuming that load balance
node is available the client will continue to get access that single node?
So, this is just a graphical depiction of the same thing here regardless of
...coming internal traffic or external traffic here you can see it's a little hard-to-read but we have
the load balanced system or service running
there in front of the web front-end or whatever front-end it is that you're running so all equally
balance across the web servers additionally of course you can use a load
balance service in the middle to your as well so,
you know, if it goes off to a back-end sequel database or
...like you can also put a load balance service in that location as well.
So, as I mentioned load balancing kind of goes hand-in-hand with availability
set so in this case the user comes down to load balance or the load bouncers distributing the
workloads equally across all the load balance nodes and you've set those load balance nodes
into and availability set to ensure that are on different...within the datacenter so this is
assuring that you're not only scaling out the workloads that are coming in or the...
are coming in but you're also protecting against single-point sere failure within the datacenter.
Ok, so, actually I want to switch over now in show some of these things
and action that we've been talking about so I think display port.
Maybe I'm not display port.
Many display...
So, close.
Okay, so, let's go ahead and bring up the portal.
here's a portal...in as myself you can see we have a number of things going on here
if I go ahead and browse you can see all the different services that I can deploy I can go into
deeper here and see my virtual machine images so I have multiple virtual machines currently
...my...your service or sorry virtual machines not images will get...images
and just a second there's my various of virtual machines and one thing I want to do is
to show how easy it is to add a disk to a virtual machine and what
that persistence side the vm itself so I've
officially named one of my virtual machines here a lots of discs?
So, if I click on lots of discs you can see some of the monitoring
information's popping up here you can see that this is based on at the for size
virtual machine if I continue to move over into the settings and move over into the
disks.
You can see I have what does it for eight is something of a range of twelve data
disks currently attached to the virtual machine again based on the size of
...that you start with you can go up to
sixty-four attach disks what I want to do is I'm going-to go ahead and attach disk.
And, earlier was talking about the caching here's an option in the you are right here if I want
to do read-only caching on this disk read write caching on
...for simplicity sake...not can do any host
caching and I'm going-to go ahead so we can see what pops up...create this...say new disk.
New disk one we're going-to go ahead and say okay.
Solver notifications you can see that's working on creating a new...that's working away
...I'm going to do is go into the virtual machine itself so this is the lots of
disk virtual machine is runningwindows server twenty twelve rtwo.
If we take a look here's the...that we talked about earlier...my see drive which...my system disk here's the
...which...temporary storage definitely don't put long-term data in there and
what I've also created here is an disc so...storage pool or stored spaces
...windows server twenty twelve so far bring it up I don't know if you have a lot of familiarity here but
what I'm trying to show is how easy it is to create a very large storage pool inside of
a virtual machine and actively ad disks and increase that storage
pool on-the-fly so if we take a look here if you're familiar with how storage pooling works and
how storage spaces works is I've created a virtual disk which is up to
thirty-two terabytes and size currently these are all the...that we saw in
as your ui that I've added into the storage pool so I think it's you gain in the looks like
...levin disks and I know that comes up here...say that I currently have
capacity for eleven disks and if I come back you can see that are new
disk has been added and
I think maybe I wasn't looking but it did look like it just said popped up?
So, here's an additional disk that came up I love the terminology here the
...primordial so I mean this is like...existence of a...doing nothing for
us right now if I come back down to the storage pool.
I can go in.
And, I can do tasks and I can add the physical disk and
I'll go ahead and pick that one terabyte...that we just created in as...you
are intellect that it doesn't take long if you spay attention up here where my cursor
isn't just a minute you'll see that are storage space inside of the running virtual machine has gone from eleven
terabytes...twelve terabytes so again we can go up to sixty-four the
beautiful thing about storage spaces in storage pooling...windows is the fact that you can add it
to an existing volume this is...simply a...volume you
...continue to grow your size inside the virtual machine okay so just in the
you why let me show you a few of the other things that we can talk about as well.
So, we'll come back over here.
And, we'll take a look at some of...or virtual machines.
Let's go over the browns.
Okay, so, I have a number of virtual machines running, for example,
just grab one of my load ballot sets and...work are three way through the settings as well if I go over
...all settings and if I take a look here's where we set up availability sets.
Sometimes are goes so you can see...availability set called av set number one
it's currently in there as a little warning is telling us is that you need to or more virtual machines in this
set to ensure the ninety nine-point nine five percent of time requirement
and you can also choose to pull out of the availability set down here's where you choose the
load balance sets as well so you can go ahead and it's going to say I'm going to do the
changes you can do a load balance set here and you can see have started to create a load balance set
number-one so when you...for easy to add availability set add
eh load balance set and add your virtual machines to that set as well
...one other thing I want to show here briefly I've to other virtual machines we talked about
...smb share if I goal
...go back into the as your portal
...go ahead and take a look at my services and if I take a look at my.
Storage accounts oops I...
Go back please storage counts.
We created a...several smb storage accounts that
are actually shared against these virtual machines again so I have to virtual machines
are actually set up to use the same files a...
So, we have number one right here and number two over here
and very simple very...my number one go she is.
So, here these are both warmly windows server ogg in their content a connected to an as your file
service which is allowing for smb file share so if I go ahead
and bring up the file share itself you can see all go ahead and
create.
A new file.
...make a text document say hello.
World.
And, right over there on the second virtual machine that's connected to the same file share
...to be expected it
shows up so again this is a great way you can have multiple virtual machines connected the same as
...btwo dot one file share inside of inside of the measure vs.
Ok.
So, let's go ahead...switch back.
...pop-up...good.
So,...extensions how many people are actually familiar with gm extensions
...only a few hands so most people are very familiar with the concept of
a virtual machine image where you know, have a container where you drop down operating system install
your applications you do all your configuration again a lot of people actually create this is a
...image than that can deploy over and over again what...extension
is basically a new method to do real-time configuration of an application
or package or script inside of the virtual machine and it could be done at
the time of deployment of the...it could also be done post
vm deployment so gives you a lot of our because you user management should
...large partner ecosystem so when you're thinking about your applications and you're thinking about development
you're thinking about how to get them deployed into casual virtual machines this is an option
that should be considered so one the key things here is when you think about creating a gold
image virtual machine usually it's a workload or something...saying I'm building a messaging
collaboration solution I want to packages a virtual machine and that's the way I want to ship it
...often times can be something like in anti-virus agent
are not necessarily going to create a gold image around a...you just one anti-virus and
anti mal where agent inside of all your virtual machines so by using extensions
in all shown...minutes we've had a lot of third-party partners build great extensions such
as anti-virus agents such as encryption options such as client
access to things like papon chef for dev ops orchestration all of
these things are easy to inject into the virtual machine so when we take a look here?
For example, through our shell through the
agent and here's just a few examples we can actually injected into the vm
...our...script we can adjust agents like the semantic anti
...where we could also inject things like the chef
...agent directly into the virtual machine microsoft
has made a number of agents or excuse me a number of extensions we've also partnered with a
number of isv or building extensions as well.
And, you can also use bash for the linux environments so this is done either through the ui we
also have additional extensions that can be deployed via bash or via our
shell directly inside the virtual machine and it just submit all go in and actually show
you the extensions and show you through the you why how to do deployment.
So, here's some examples of extensions that
we have available today we have darker we have you know,
simple things simple scripts and tools as well such as reset
passwords so again have a running virtual machine you want...to a simple reset of
a password you go ahead and inject that script the nice thing again is either through
the wire through our shell you can put in all your specific parameters
so as you'll see in the demo when you install something like
...mel were agent will actually ask you questions...say where's your
...server you'll...this is the location of my server or this is my license key
will take that user-defined data and during the injection of the agent itself or the
extension itself will use that custom user-defined information so
again all across-the-board here chef and puppet trend micro semantic visual studio
the script extensions our shell ccs all kinds of things.
And, then this one is kinda near and dear to my heart kind of injected this in here this is the
...marketplace as your marketplaces something that we've been focusing on a bit
as application developers you may be familiar but what we're trying to do is grab great applications both
first party and from our partners and have a central location both in as ram
...authenticated on the web where you can
profiles you can find virtual machines you can deploy
virtual machines directly into your browser subscription back to tech at a few months ago we
...that we had over fifty partners that we've worked with the build great new images
into the asher marketplace sincewe've added dozens and dozens more were really
starting to engage to build a great ecosystem as you're building your apps is your
warning to get them out there if there for general use and consumption think about the
...marketplace we have monitors a shun options as well our partners
or building applications and putting them into the marketplace or using typically one of
to methods either number-one hourly building directly to router so
you actually go through during the publishing process and you identify what you want
a bill for your application on top of the general algebra consumption
so you say for a for virtual machine I want to build x cents per hour for you know,
...for virtual machine I want to build why since per hour additionally we allow
for the bring what we refer to as by aol are bring...license model
so if you already have customers who you know,have licensing contracts
...site licenses with you and all they want to do is basically user licensing
...application...of asher you can use that as well so a lot of our partners
and a lot of our app developers are building both bring your own license versions of
the software as well as leveraging...your...goal with the big, you know,
with the pages you go the customer basically gets one
bill from microsoft which includes asher compute and the cost
for the application from the eyes free...what we do is we gather that money
and pay back the application developer the iso...for the software?
Ok, so, let's actually look back in.
The system looks like a look at some of the u.
So, if I go back in I just create a new my up I am.
A new virtual machine...new we're going to compute we're
going to go down to...marketplace so right here integrated into the portal is the
marketplaceyou could excuse me you can also go again on
as your dot com there's a link to the marketplace as well so even if you don't want to be authenticated or
login as you can see all the different workloads that are available you can see
has broken up into many different things under virtual machines I can click the more option and
then it's going to show you lots in theory lots.
In theory of virtual machines
five four three two one.
There's lots they all looks like a popped up and then away.
Long-running there are wonderful verge very good so these are
just in alphabetical order you can see solutions all across-the-board from alert larger you know,
barracuda has solutions and here we have solutions from river bed we have core os which
is platform images anything that you can possibly want so if we just keep
it real simple we're going-to go ahead and select one of our virtual machines here this is
windows server nice and basic let's go twenty twelve rtwo is fine.
We'll go ahead and say creates...brings...options are given a name if
...me there goes the scallops bryan.
User name.
You know-how hard it is from you actually type my password with...verbally saying
as I type so I was very good of me not to do that.
If we keep going on...we go into optional configuration.
Right here's where we can bring extensions into this virtual machine as I as I mentioned you can do
...of deployment and you can also do a post deployment as well so if I add extension.
Here's some of the ones that are in the marketplace right now there's also...lot more that are
outside of the marketplace that...be bringing in short-order before example we have chef we have
...if I go in and just select the microsoft anti
mail where one and if I click create.
You can see it's going to ask me for some of the parameters so again this is the user parameters that right here in the
you why or through our shel we can basically set and say
with the endpoint is what is conducting to with the licensing type is an during vm creation we can go
ahead and deploy that extension ok.
So, let's switch back one more time.
And, actually without...right back to
...very goal so here's the clicker andthank you very much I think brian.
All right so I'm going to close out with awith basically...a little bit about what's new and,
you and open with isowill go through this and,...we've got so just
to give you a sense of just like how we view the overall compute continuum in the world here
review it sort of in this ultimate control rapid deployment sort of continuum
right so vm is always the left and this is sort of complete
control complete ability to configure every single detail you want them
extensions a little bit further along right it's going to it's going to do some of configuration for you it's going to
automate some things for you I makes it easier but it's still sort of that underlying
vm still underneath then you go further the right and we've got service called asher batch
in-service fabric which now you've seen or heard of which takes a little bit more...still
running on a vm you still can sort of log on and it feels like a vm but it's going to it's going to take care
...for-you and in taking care of those things you're giving it control right you're saying
you take care of my data replication right you take care of the fact that I have quorum
on my application so that is sort of what the your handing off when you move
to service fabric and then all the way to the right some of our higher-level higher-level
paths services that offer really that fast really fast of deployment
really easy to go but, then have a little bit less control...you're really giving a lot of
control the platform when you deploy up service whether be web...mobile whether we logic
...all of these end up having a lot-a lot of the control sort of given for that rapid deployment
so how do these things all come together well I'm glad that I ask...to answer so the resource
...the as a resource manager which is a json
base template in this was the announcement that we actually just made
we made this afternoon it wasn't made this morning we save it for the afternoon the afternoon
wave announcements and this is support actually it's been out for a while to be clear but we
added support for a virtual machines networking in storage to this so this available today
in public preview and you can now pieced together in a single template
virtual machines next load bouncers all these aspects with
...services as well sequel db web app
...and have a...large application that puts all these pieces together it also brings
role base access control on the api today...access control for...
is only through the portal it now you can be controlled at the api level as well
you can do tagging on top of that and then of course the whole template languages really some of the benefits
and I'm going to walk you through a few of those as an example?
Ok, so, as part of this I'm just going to pull up my blog
and it's going to have you read it on the screen.
As we know not okay that's not the real them I...you've got so,
some of the things for the for the way that you deployed this the new resources that we've just
expose on the left vietnam's next load bouncer security groups public
...nets these can now all be defined as json objects as part of
a template language they could all have dependencies between them right so
you can in fact you will require dependencies to do some things you want to do like you
...sub...you probably need the neck to be created first so you'll say create my neck
then only then can you create my vm so these sorts dependencies can exist other
through really cool things about this parameters you can pass them all the way through you can pass...all the way down
to your extensions so even some of the most crude types of examples you put
a our shell extension that runs on the box you pass
...parameter down you can do pretty much anything on that virtual
machines same thing with our bash extension and we're seeing a lot of application developers who
have typically come in and said I'm going to create an image and I'm going to
put it in the gallery now saying I'm just actually going to bring down my app
on-the-fly and install it because now I don't have to patch the os so this brings together a lot
of that capability with the ability to run those scripts and that extension on the box with
a template to be able to reuse it over and over again parallel deployment as I mentioned
deploying ten fifteen twenty virtual machines at once is not a problem
it's something that actually the system was built to do and, actually can handle
it very quickly because actually this api is running on top of a service fabric
ring underneath it which is sort of mind-blowing because service fabric when you run it will run on top of these
...but these vent the
...api is actually running as a service on service fabric because of the
throughput that's required for the api calls that are coming in other things that we have the ability to
do loops so you actually can go in and put a single vm and you can make
...deploy two hundred times and will pate will take the loop parameter and
...attach it onto the names of that resource as
its deploying and then actual as I mentioned we have three fd so
...domains you can now deploy so one of the things I'll say I'll say this at the end there's a
deep dive tomorrow that's going to go through every single example
and every single resource that I mentioned here and explain how to use
...pieces together so on I'm just going to give you a few examples and what we've actually released with
this is we've actually launched a set of templates for you to go get started with or use to
actually spin of virtual machines that you want to develop on so great example we have we have a
jenkins deployment among...a couple...dvds the solutions
...goes you keeper sharepoint apache our
shell all of these are available in our current is actually in a get help repository that I'll
show you and index on as your dot com to deploy or learn from
right is either way you want to use the jenkins box you...just deploy it and play with it or
you can read how we did it and learn from it to build your own you can even forget straight their and build
...get help?
So, this kind of...me into some...got some sort of...additional point here a lot of the examples that I
gave you why a lot of the rest microsoft hates me is in fact the
open-source beard we do talk...a lot in the team and
it's actually amazing because before when I did not have a beard this is what I look like?
I don't have that tiny more no, but, it is one of the things that we do spend a lot of time
and the team making sure the open-source solutions work great and it's
something we're really passion about...so this is a great example this is are
...integration you've heard a lot about this I'm actually not going to spend too much time on it but,
we do have a deep...
relationship in fact one of the temples I will show you is a dockers story we have the ability to
work deploy a full swarm cluster right now using a template that's one of the temple
to actually have already including we have the dc os for
may sphere as well some...things that are coming a deeper integration with
...hub into the asher gallery you'll be able to deploy straight from doc or hub and a
couple of container solutions that we've talked about pretty extensively already
ok and to walk through sort of examples of how these templates really working action brian gave some
of the details but we're using templates like this to be able to deploy things that you already have in
the portal today and this kind of gives you an example of some of the our that you have being able to deploy
...directly out-of-the-box uses this template model...able
...octopus uses it visual studio released managers already using it to be able to
deploying manage virtual machines that it's that it's a running inside the
...inside of asher and of course chef puppet...are all using it to be able to
configure the virtual machines when you deploy so as brian said the combination of
the template parameters using extensions makes all this possible.
The other thing that we announce today that I'm not going to spend too much time on but
worth talking about this api has opened up an entire additional wave of
...solutions that can run asher so it's not just service fabric which is a great
product but we also announced today partnerships with cloud foundries
a brenda angie elastic to be able to support all
...solutions on top of asher so there are running on top of this
new api because of the agility in the flexibility to deploy and
...very exciting to be able to have again this open story of
...solutions on as your piecing these things together you could have
cloud foundries talking to sequel db I mean you can imagine the options
are really limitless of course service fabric the one that we've that we've announced as well so when you sort of look at
the overall story for open operating systems a wide variety including freebie
sd a wide set a linux offers as well.
Data, you know, the drill
...db we have oracle support as well as ibm db and,
my sequel offering and of course sap supported
...development perspective just across-the-board and this is not necessarily just I as...really asher in
general the overall mobile story and that language story and even the new
as support for the api is that we have will be releasing st
...actually we have one available for node today will be releasing one for
java very soon to be able to code directly to those and of course the
...is node as well...of course tooling and I'm going to show you visual studio in
the two minutes I have left and, walk you through so what that looks like so
with that let me I'm going to go to my demo here and just show you a few things and, then
you'll be on your way so let me start here with.
Sorry...this so.
Go-to community and go-to templates a new section and
here you'll see templates that are index directly from get up so you add a template into
our get have repository it will show up on as your dot com and give you an example of this
it automatically searches for it so let me go to mine template so you'll see there's my ugly mug here
at the top it actually pulls the picture of the get have owner who created it will show I thought I
put description for my parameters that's a shame you can actually put in your parameters of what you're going to deploy here
and it will automatically update this...the best part about this is you
...deployed to asher and actually will automatically go in
into your asher account authenticate you the template shows up in the
poorly can edit here if you want to if you don't you hit save.
And, then you go...you put in your parameters and deploy as just amazingly simple to take
a very complex thing and deploy it within moments.
And, this is all indexed in get hub like I said so the get hub
location as your as your quick start templates and you can go in here
you can fork and learn everything you want to learn.
So, here you can see if I go to jungle app and going here.
Click on it and there's the template ready to roll okay and
the very last thing here is how many actually want to
...session this morning ok phew well let me just quickly
show you this whole language noun visual studio is completely available to you go
in and update and modify and play with and they're going to spend a lot of time
in this in the deep dive tomorrow but just to kinda give you a few examples here if I want to go
in and here's the overall template you see here on the right let's see here zoomed...
here okay so you can see here my parameters are all listed out and,
I can, you know, go in and actually monitor them and I can go find them in my
template so let's see virtual machine name that's...that and I'll show you
...the template...location for that parameter to straying the description that comes
in that metadata and then I can go in and do plus and I can add all sorts of things
...a template language I can add a neck right here if I wanted to I can added
powerful dac extension sequel server virtual network and you go in
and if you hit this and say yep that's to tests...add it goes in it actually
drops it right into by into my overall script and I can go in
...the dependencies here and play with it so the our of visual studio added
on top of these extensions should really make this a lot of fun to go play with
...like I said they're going to spend a ton of time on this tamar the deep dive and that's kind of kind of the
overall the endpoint here so go see the deep dive on thursday guys you know,
overall I hope this...valuable to...and,
go sign up if you haven't signed up for msdn that's a great deal great offer for-you and,
send-me something on twitter as well so they get so much will be here to answer some questions afterwards if you want?